# **ADEL SAKKIR**

#### **PROFILE**

Experienced in building analytical and optimization solutions for a startup in Dubai to generate over £0.5 million in annual cost savings. Feel free to review my projects on operations research, machine learning and simulations on my github profile

#### **EDUCATION**

#### London School of Economics and Political Science,

2023 - 2024

MSc. Operations Research and Analytics (Department of Mathematics) *⊗* 

<u>Modules:</u> Mathematical & Combinatorial Optimisation, Algorithms, Reinforcement Learning, Modelling and Simulation <u>Dissertation</u>: Development and Implementation of Dreyfus-Wagner algorithm and iterative local search for Steiner Trees

#### Indian Institute of Technology (IIT), Roorkee,

2022 – 2023 | Online

Post Graduate Certificate in Strategic Supply Chain with AI

Modules: Mathematical Modelling, Machine Learning, Data Visualisation, MILP Solvers, Supply Chain Management

## Indian Institute of Technology (IIT), Kharagpur,

2018 - 2022

BTech (Honours) Industrial Engineering (GPA: 8.26/10.0)

Micro Specialisation: Entrepreneurship and Innovation (GPA: 10.0/10.0)

Modules: Probability and Statistics, Optimization and Heuristic Methods, Operations Research, Linear Algebra

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Business Analyst (Instock), noon.com @

09/2022 – 08/2023 | Dubai, UAE

15 member team growing "noon in minutes" (quick commerce startup) from 5 to 50+ stores across the UAE (10000+ SKUs)

- Developed a **stochastic inventory model** for perishables to achieve an annual cost saving of **1.5 million AED (£320k)** to maximize product availability and minimize disposals (**Fast Moving SKUs Normal, Slow SKUs Poisson**)
- Deployed a **multiple linear regression** model replenish "fruits and vegetables" category based on price, seasonality, sales history resulting in an annual cost saving of **1.2 million AED** (£260k)
- Optimized the stock transfer algorithm between warehouse and stores to improve monthly product availability by 20%
- Built **5+ KPI dashboards** to generate reports on fill rate, inventory, disposals with DataStudio and BigQuery
- Automated the shipment booking process using Selenium saving 70+ man hours per week

#### **Supply Chain Analyst Intern,** Covvalent *∂*

05/2022 - 07/2022 | Delaware (Remote), USA

Early stage startup building B2B procurement solution for the global specialty chemicals market

- Scraped export/import data of 100+ suppliers from South Asia to catelogue 1500+ products and specifications
- Generated an annual demand of \$0.5 Million (£400k) from paint manufacturers in the US to export chemicals
- Conducted 15+ stakeholder interviews to identify trends in purchasing, delivery and quality

#### **PROJECTS**

## Parallel machine scheduling - MILP & Genetic Algorithms,

09/2023

Flexciton, London 🔗

- Developed a MILP and a genetic algorithm formulation to optimise a semiconductor manufacturing schedule
- Achieved an **improvement of 17%** in cycle time (10 machines and 100 orders) compared to present solution

## Travelling Salesman and Knapsack Solver (Personal Project),

08/2023

Discrete Optimisation, Prof. Pascal Van H., Georgia Institute of Technology *⊘* 

- Solving knapsack and tsp problems of varying sizes (upto 10,000 items(knapsack), 500 cities (tsp))
- Knapsack Implemented **branch and bound techniques (bfs/dfs), dynamic programming** and other greedy approaches
- TSP Implemented MILP, 2 OPT, 3 OPT, and randomised local search techniques to minimise tour length
- Generated a comprehensive report on run time and storage requirements with respect to input size

#### **Supplier Risk Prediction, Classification,** *Prof. G. Dixit, IIT Roorkee ⊘*

07/2023

- Trained classification models based on 1000 suppliers and 20+ feature variables to predict supplier default risk Logistic Regression, ADA Boost, XG Boost, Decision Tree, Random Forest
- Selected best performing model based on ROC curves, Accuracy, Sensitivity, Specificity, F1 Score, AUC
- Incorporated predicted probability into an IP optimisation model to minimise cost of procurement

#### Other Projects &

Stochastic Inventory Modelling (Perishable Goods), Discrete Event Simulation(Queues), Sudoku

## TECHNICAL SKILLS AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Languages and Software: Python, SQL, R, MATLAB, Google AppScripts, AMPL, Excel
- Libraries: Sklearn, Numpy, Pandas, Scipy, Selenium, BeautifulSoup, ortools, Matplotlib, PuLP, pyomo
- Mathematics for Machine Learning Specialisation: 3 Course, Imperial College London
- Advanced Statistics for Data Science Specialisation: 2 Course, John Hopkins University